Hello everyone and welcome to
English Pod. My name is Marco.
Hi everyone. My name is Catherine.
What do you got Catherine for us today?
It's a good question. Well, we've
got a little bit of a Seinfeld situation
So for those of you who
are not familiar with this
American TV show, which by
the way is one of my favorites
Seinfeld is a TV show
A comedy about very awkward,
very common situations that
are taken to the extreme,
right? So it's a very popular show
It was around for like 10 years. Oh, yeah.
Yeah, and but it's not airing anymore
Well, they're not making
new episodes anymore.
No, you have to see them
in reruns reruns, right?
So we have a situation that's very common.
It was and it was pretty funny on the show
It's a guide trying to rent a
car. Okay, so he's probably
at the airport or traveling
and he he's had a long flight
And they want to rent a car, but
of course there are some problems.
So this is an elementary
level lesson by the way
So keep that in mind as we
listen to this dialogue one time
Hi, I made a reservation for a midsize
vehicle. The name is Jimmy Fox. I'm sorry
We have no midsize
available at the moment.
I don't understand. I made a
reservation. Do you have my reservation?
Yes, we do
Unfortunately, we ran out of cars
But the reservation keeps
the car here. That's why you
have the reservation. I know
why we have reservations
I don't think you do if you
did I'd have a car see you know
how to take the reservation.
You just don't know how to
Hold the reservation and
that's really the most important
part of the reservation the
holding anybody can just take them
But we do have a compact
or an SUV if you'd like
Fine, I'll take the compact
All right, we have a blue Ford focus for
you mr. Fox. Would you like insurance?
Yeah, you better give
me the insurance because
I'm gonna beat the
hell out of this car
All right, great, so this
actually happens a lot
you make a reservation
and either they lose it or
They run out of cars.
It's such a common situation
And it's not just cars
sometimes this happens
at restaurants - and it
really makes me angry
Yeah, that happens a lot
you show up and they're like
oh, we don't have a
reservation and you're just like
Well, then you have to
keep yourself in check.
You can't really get
angry, but this guy does
So let's take a look at the
language take away to find out
what are some of the words
we're using here to describe
Renting a car and what
kind of car we're talking about
Language take away
Well, as you mentioned At rental places they
have different size cars right different
size vehicles which by the
way it costs different prices right
So let's take a look at the
sizes that they mentioned
in dialogue and starting
with the cheapest one the least
Expensive and the smallest.
It's a compact vehicle.
All right compact. So compact
actually means small small
Right, so compact car you're gonna
hear very often even if you're buying a car
Let's think of an idea.
What's what's a compact car? The VW Golf
Is a compact car very small car usually
it's two doors or if it's a four-door car
It's very small not very long, right?
Right exactly
So maybe like a four
focus could be a small car
also compact now moving up in size a
little bit We would have a mid-size vehicle
Okay mid-size vehicle is well, it's a
giveaway here because mid-meads middle
So it's kind of in the middle
between the small and
the large and this is your
average four-door sedan car
Okay, so as an example you would have a
Ford Taurus or maybe a Toyota Camry. Yeah
Toyota Camry has made the most common car
Yeah, that's kind of expensive,
but it still midsize right
exactly and now a bigger car and
probably one of the most popular
Cars in the United States is
an SUV not anymore Marco.
I know if the energy
crisis and the gas prices
Well, the economy as well people
are not driving their SUVs anymore
But uh SUV is an acronym.
That means it stands
for three different
words S meaning sports
You meaning utility
V vehicle. All right.
Thank you So SUV sport utility vehicle
means it can go maybe off-road right
So an example of this
would be a Ford Explorer or
a Cherokee a Jeep Cherokee
could be an SUV as well
So right those are three
different types of cars
now obviously there are
many more like a van or a
Limo a limo like a limousine
here, but yeah, these are
the most common ones that you
would rent at a car rental Yes, definitely
But what we have to do
here is make a reservation
Mm-hmm now interesting
you make a reservation.
Yeah, you don't have it.
You don't do it. You don't
You make it. Yeah, you make
these are words that go together
So we're gonna keep them together.
I can call a restaurant
So a safer example Marco
works at a restaurant say hello.
I'd like to make a
reservation for tonight
Okay, perfect now if you show
up at the restaurant you say
Where's my table? I made
a reservation right and of
course I throw a fit because
there's nothing for me
So you make a reservation
and in this case it was
made before okay, so
you make a reservation now
Why was this guy angry
at the rental car place?
Long story short the company
Ran out of cars. Okay, not all cars just
the car that he wanted the midsize vehicle
So they ran out so that doesn't mean
they're actually running somewhere
No, they have putting on their
running shoes and going for a jog
No, in this case to
run out or in this case
we ran out means that they don't have
anymore You don't have anymore exactly
I think this word is a nice word for us to
take a look at some other examples now
Example one
We're going to run out of gasoline.
You need to find a gas station soon
Example two
Can you buy some milk on your way home?
We ran out last night
Example three
My pen ran out of ink.
Can you lend me one please?
Not a fun phrase, but an important
one in case you're ever in a restaurant or
in a hotel or in a place where you can
purchase something or rent something
And it's all gone. All
right, so I think we've
taken a look at a lot of great words
here So let's listen to this dialogue again
We're gonna slow it
down just a little bit and
then we'll come back
and explain some phrases
Hi, I made a reservation for a
midsize vehicle. The name is Jimmy Fox
I'm sorry.
We have no midsize available at the moment
I don't understand. I made a reservation.
Do you have my reservation?
Yes, we do
Unfortunately, we ran out of cars
But the reservation keeps
the car here. That's why you
have the reservation. I know
why we have reservations
I don't think you do if you did.
I'd have a car see you know
how to take the reservation
You just don't know how to hold the
reservation and that's really the most
important part of the reservation
the holding anybody can just take them
But we do have a compact
or an SUV if you'd like
Fine, I'll take the compact
All right, we have a blue Ford focus for
you mr. Fox. Would you like insurance?
Yeah, you better give
me the insurance because
I'm gonna beat the
hell out of this car
And we're back so Marco. We've got a couple
phrases here that deserve some attention
So let's take a look at them
in today's fluency builder
Fluency builder
So the first phrase that
we want that I want to
take a look at is when
the agent says I'm sorry
We have no midsize
available at the moment
Okay, so do they or do they not have any?
Yeah, she says that we have no midsize
Okay, so another way to
say this is we haven't got any
We don't have any okay, but in this case
you can just simplify it and say we have no
Why wouldn't she say we
have none good question why?
Because we need a thing here. We have
no cars. We have no cake. We have no food
So this is a very common phrase in English
and remember to put the thing at the end so
For example, can I say I have no money?
Absolutely. I'm so sorry
Marco, but I'm not gonna lend.
I have no money seriously
lend me something
So we have no this is interesting because
this is not a structure that is usually
Learned through textbooks,
right? Usually say I don't have or we
haven't got exactly this is very
spoken because you would never say
I go no right exactly
Right we have to talk
about something that we
Has an object something
that we have so here.
I have no is very spoken very
common. It's got another phrase
That is also not taught so
much in those textbooks that
we were just mentioning so
what's that phrase at the end?
Well, well, it's a threat.
The guy is so angry.
He leans over the counter
and he points his finger in the
The agent's face. What do
you say? He says yeah, you
better give me the insurance.
You better you better
All right, so you better than me.
No, no, it's not like better
Like something is good, right?
You'd better is like a suggestion.
We're a very strong one
Okay, very strong. This is a
threat. Yeah, it's you better
eat your dinner or I'm going
to send you to your room
Exactly. So as you can see it says he says
you better you better give me the insurance
But the grammatically correct way
would be you had better you had better
So you the contraction would be you'd
better exactly you'd you had better do this
So this is a it's a hypothetical
situation you had better
do this if you don't do
this bad things will happen
So remember that here we've
got the grammatically correct form
that you should write you'd
better or they spoken for you better
You better I think in this one We should
also listen to some other examples to get a
better idea of how we can
use this very strong suggestion
Example one
You better go to the doctor
before that cold gets any worse
Example two
You better watch out if
dangerous to go out this late
Example three
She better change her attitude
or her boss is going to fire her
So what is the threat you better give me
insurance because what is he gonna do?
He says I'm gonna beat
the hell out of this car
Okay, so it's future.
I'm going to I'm gonna
Beat the hell out of this car
So this is very strong right?
Yeah, it's very strong
And he's saying he is going
to destroy the car so beat
the hell out of so that
means really just do damage
Just to something so you can
use it as towards a person also.
It's like I'm going to beat the
hell out of you and I'll arrest you
Right, so it's a
very strong phrase.
It shows anger. It shows that
you are threatening somebody
So it's not obviously it's not polite
And it might get you a
broken nose and a bar if
you ever say this to
someone or about someone
So be very careful
right, but you can use it
to describe a situation
right? He's like yeah
We went to a bar yesterday and
Dan beat the hell out of the bartender
Right, man, so instead of just saying Dan
hit the bartender or Dan got into a fight
He you're saying he hit
him and he just and he kept
hitting it and kept
hitting it and kept hitting
him so yeah He beat
the hell out of him right
All right great
So those are the the phrases and
words that we wanted to talk about today
But I think it'd be good if we
listen to this dialogue one more time
Just to get a good feel
for it. We come back.
We'll be talking a little bit more
about the process of renting a car
Hi, I made a reservation for a
midsize vehicle. The name is Jimmy Fox
I'm sorry. We have no midsize
available at the moment.
I don't understand. I made a
reservation. Do you have my reservation?
Yes, we do unfortunately we ran out of cars
But the reservation keeps the car here.
That's why you have the reservation
I know why we have reservations. I don't
think you do if you did. I'd have a car
See you know how to take the reservation
You just don't know how to hold the
reservation and that's really the most
important part of the reservation
the holding anybody can just take them
But we do have a compact
or an SUV if you'd like
Fine, I'll take the compact
All right, we have a blue Ford focus for
you mr. Fox. Would you like insurance?
Yeah, you better give
me the insurance because
I'm gonna beat the
hell out of this car
You know, I heard
that in Florida or in
certain like cities of
California and Florida
You can actually rent luxury cars. Oh,
yeah, you can do that in most places.
You can rent like a Porsche
or a Lamborghini or a Ferrari
Yeah, obviously it costs a lot of money
But it gives you the opportunity
to maybe drive to maybe drive one
of these cars that you obviously
wouldn't have the money to buy
Yeah, especially if you're
talking about those warm places
like Florida or California you
want to be in the sunshine
You get a convertible. Yeah, you
got to get a convertible. Yeah, so I
think the insurance premiums on
those particular cars are very high though
So you're not only paying
for the car, but you're also
paying for the insurance and
possibly the speeding tickets
Yeah, of course. I can't
imagine renting one of
those cars and not getting
a speeding ticket exactly
So if any of you out
there have experienced
renting cars or you have
some questions about the
Specifics that are involved in this process.
Let us know on our website EnglishPod.
com. Right. We're there to
answer any questions or doubts
And we'll see you guys there.
All right until next time everyone